[music: "My Bias, My Boss" theme song]
(This drama is a work of fiction)
(Any similarity to real people, organizations, or events is coincidental)
[Hagi grunts] [intriguing music] (Hagi) Luni.
If someone gives wine as a gift
And says it's a gift from the heart, what does it mean?
Plus, I heard it's a wine known for making your love come true.
[Luni whispering] Phrases like that are used
When expressing
Their romantic interest.
Romantic...
Interest?
(Luni) She must have feelings for you!
[ding sound]
[music stops] [phone vibrating]
(Chan)
(Lee Chan) Dareum, I'll be away for a few days starting tomorrow.
Can I see you for a moment before I go?
[lively music]
(Hagi) She...
Likes me?
[footsteps approaching]
[laughs]
[cat meowing sound]
[sparkling sound] [music fades]
Let's go. I'll walk you home.
(Dareum) It's okay.
I have somewhere I need to stop by. I can go by myself.
But...
(Hagi) I should still walk you home...
(Dareum) Mr. Kang, are you all right?
Of course I am.
Why wouldn't I be?
You're acting a bit odd,
And your face is red...
[intriguing music]
(Hagi) Just...
Just go now. [comical sound]
- (Dareum) What? - I take back my offer.
I take it back!
(Hagi) Just go now. [Dareum exhales]
(Dareum) Okay.
I'll get going, then.
[rustles]
Bye.
[door opens]
[music stops] [door closes]
[door lock sound]
[Hagi sighs]
This one is obviously heavier.
They're not the same at all.
Why does my mom seem to like Kang Hagi more than her own son?
[door closes]
She's unbelievable.
[intriguing music]
[creak sound]
(Minwoo) What?
Why is a woman coming out of that house?
[door opens] [music stops]
(Minwoo) Who was that?
[door closes] Who is she?
(Episode 5) Why would an employee visit your house?
And what's with those lovestruck eyes? [thuds]
(Hagi) I had a proposal to fix urgently, so she came to help me. Okay?
(Minwoo) But I feel like I've seen her somewhere...
[intriguing music] [rustling]
Right!
The nosebleed! The ice! [ding sounds]
Right? The one who threw the drunken fit last time! [swish sound]
Wow... [Minwoo laughs]
And she's your employee now?
(Hagi) Mind your own business.
(Minwoo) What?
Wow, wine...
So work was just an excuse. That was a date, wasn't it? [smacks]
I didn't prepare it. She bought it for me,
(Hagi) and said it was a gift from the heart.
(Minwoo) No way! Then she's the one who asked you out?
[whoosh sound] [music stops]
(Hagi) Well...
She didn't say it directly, but... [exciting music]
(Dareum) Mr. Kang, drink this [whoosh sound]
And cheer up.
Hang in there! [whoosh sound]
[comical sound] (Hagi) I mean...
She walked up to me
And told me to cheer up.
(Dareum) Mr. Kang! [whoosh sound]
I'll sit next to you.
[grunts]
(Hagi) She suddenly keeps touching me... [whoosh sound]
Gosh...
And more than anything...
[heart beating sound] [laughs]
[heartbeat growing faster]
She smiles whenever she sees me.
Wow...
(Hagi) She must
Like me, right?
No. [music stops]
[Hagi grunts]
(Minwoo) Not just "like."
It's "love."
Love. [voice echoes] [heart beating sound]
[passionate music] (Hagi) What?
Love?
[whoosh sound]
Love.
[sparkling sound]
[whistling sound]
Love.
[footsteps fading] [music stops]
[thuds] [Hagi reacts]
[faint dog barking] [insects chirping]
(Chan Can I see you for a moment before I go?)
[notification ping]
(Youverse Lee Chan started a livestream)
Hi. It's been a while, hasn't it? [emotional music]
(Lee Chan on screen) I have to leave early tomorrow,
So I can't talk long.
I just...
Wanted to see you all.
I can't see your faces, but you can see me.
I wanted to say something to you.
I know I can be immature
And hurt you sometimes,
But thank you for always supporting me.
I really mean it.
[faint sigh]
[Lee Chan clears throat on screen]
I read in one of my favorite books
That in time, your sincerity will always come through.
So I hope my sincerity reaches you too.
It's late.
I should go to bed now.
I'll come back next time. Bye.
(The livestream has ended) [clicks] [beeps]
[sighs] [phone vibrating]
(Dareum) I don't have time today. I'll see you next time. [message notification sound]
[message notification sound]
And you don't need to worry
About what happened that day.
(Lee Chan) Thanks for messaging me back, Dareum. [message notification sound]
[message notification sound] (Dareum) I hope the shoot goes well.
I'll be rooting for you.
[faint laugh]
[insects chirping]
[phone clacks]
[sighs]
[music stops]
[street sounds]
[intriguing music]
(Hagi) Get a grip, Kang Hagi!
Just act...
Like you normally do.
[card reader beeps]
[sighs]
[music stops]
[footsteps approaching]
[sparkling sound]
(Hagi) Oh...
Thank... [Dareum grunts] [cheerful music]
[heart beating sound] you...
Mr. Kang,
(Dareum) did you find any more stickers at home?
It was pretty fun yesterday. It was like a treasure hunt.
- If you find any more... - Ms. Nam.
(Dareum) Yes? [music stretches and stops]
We're at work.
[Dareum reacts]
[whoosh sound] [intriguing music] I'm the CEO.
(CEO) [thud sounds]
[comical sound] (Hagi) And you're an employee.
(Employee) [thud sounds]
Let's... [whoosh sound]
Keep things... [whoosh sound]
Professional.
[blinking sound]
[whoosh sound]
[flaps]
[comical sound]
[Dareum gasps] [Hagi huffs]
(Dareum) Oh, my gosh! [elevator dings]
[music stops] [elevator doors opening]
[buttons beeping] (automated voice) Doors... Doors... Doors closing.
Mr. Kang! [cheerful music]
(Dareum) Mr. Kang, let me... [banging]
What?
What's going on with him?
What did I do wrong this time? [music stops]
[Jinsang clears throat]
[employees murmuring]
[relief sound] [Jinsang clears throat]
[Jinsang clears throat]
Excuse me. Sorry. [Jinsang clears throat]
I have to go out to the front when Mr. Kang calls me later,
So give me some space.
(Miyeong) You? Why?
(Jinsang) What do you mean, why?
Look. "K-Wave project." It's worth 1.5 billion won.
[Jinsang laughs]
- Want to take a look? - (Sungwook) Really?
(Jinsang) Yeah.
(Sungwook) "Dalgona-shaped keychain that has a sweet taste."
Is this really all a grown-up can come up with?
This is definitely getting rejected.
(Jinsang) Hey!
This is definitely going to attract bugs.
- (Jinsang) What? - (Miyeong) Yeah.
(Sungwook) I hope it goes well. [Miyeong reacts]
- (Jinsang) That look... - (Hagi) Let's begin the meeting.
[Jinsang grunts]
[beeps] We held an internal competition
To submit proposals for the K-Wave project organized by the Korea Heritage Service.
(Hagi) I'll announce the winner today.
[drumroll sound] Since there was only one spot
For the fashion category, the item was the most important factor.
The selected idea is...
[laughs]
Lee...
[Jinsang exclaims and exhales]
[drumroll stops]
[beeps] Mina's mosaic wrapping cloth.
[employees gasp] (Dareum) Oh, my gosh!
(Dareum, Yeongwoo) Wow! [employees clap]
[bright music] [Dareum, Yeongwoo exclaim]
- (Miyeong) Sit down. - (Sungwook) Sit down, dalgona.
(Yeongwoo) Ms. Lee, congratulations!
Amazing.
(Hagi) Ms. Lee, why don't you come to the front and explain your idea?
Okay!
[Yeongwoo exclaims]
[Mina gasps] [employees cheer and clap]
(Yeongwoo) You're so cool!
[Jinsang claps loudly]
[Mina gasps] [music stops]
[Mina exclaims] Hello.
(Mina) I'm a new employee on the MD team,
[off-pitch] Lee Mina...
[bright music] [laughing]
[employees laugh quietly]
- Nice to meet you... - (Yeongwoo) She's nervous.
[gasps]
[beeps] Well...
(Mina) The item I came up with
Is a mosaic wrapping cloth,
Inspired by traditional Korean patchwork.
We'll be collaborating with a textile shop in Jongno
That's been in business for three generations.
[beeps]
Since Korean patchwork
Is very similar to mosaics and stained glass,
I believe it will also feel familiar to customers overseas.
Wow. It's really pretty.
Thank you! [employees clap and cheer]
(Yeongwoo) You're so cool!
[Jinsang claps loudly]
I'd like the marketing team
And the MD team to collaborate on this project.
(Miyeong, Yeongwoo) Yes, sir!
[music stops]
[emotional music plays] [Lee Chan blows]
[squeaking sound]
(stylist 1) What's that? It's so cute.
(Lee Chan) My fan drew this character, and it was so cute I memorized it.
(stylist 2) But what is this, though?
Is it a bear or a pig? [stylist 2 laughs]
(Lee Chan) You're right.
The nose is a pig's,
But the ears look like a bear's...
(stylist 2) It looks more like a pig, right? [stylists laugh]
- (Wonbin) They're asking for you. - (stylist 2) Oh, gosh.
- (stylist 1) We'll get going now. - (Wonbin) Okay.
- (stylist 2) Hang in there. - (Wonbin) You too.
- Here. - (Lee Chan) Thank you.
What would you have done without that photobook?
What do you like about it so much? You carry it around like a lucky charm.
It just...
Makes me feel better.
[calm music]
Whenever I wonder if it's okay to continue my career
Or if I'll be able to keep receiving love from my fans
And lose confidence,
(Lee Chan) it feels like this book is telling me to go on.
(Wonbin) The fan who made you this probably won't even imagine
[Lee Chan laughs] that it's become your favorite item.
They're probably not my fan anymore.
It was ten years ago.
[Lee Chan, Wonbin laugh]
(Wonbin) Right. It's been ages.
Who could be that dedicated? [Wonbin sighs]
(Dareum) I've liked you for 12 years. How would I not know that?
I know you're a good person.
And if you've made an effort to seem like a good person until now,
That already makes you
A good enough person.
[laughs]
There is...
One person. [music fades]
[ominous music]
(SE Trading) [birds singing]
(Miyeong) Why is there a SE Trading car...
No way...
Just a moment.
- (manager) Thank you for accepting. - (shop owner) No problem.
[shop owner laughs]
(Mina) Sir.
[shop owner reacts]
(shop owner) Hi, Mina.
(Mina) What is all this?
Don't you remember that you were going to sign a contract with us today?
Well...
(shop owner) Gosh... I'm sorry.
SE Trading
Came to me with a similar proposal,
And their terms were much better.
(Mina) But sir...
I showed this mosaic wrapping cloth
To you first.
But how could SE Trading...
(shop owner) Well...
I mean, it's possible for you
To come up with similar ideas, right? [Miyeong scoffs]
(Mina) What?
[Miyeong sighs]
(manager) Ms. Nam Dareum. [whoosh sound]
That's not something you need to worry about, Ms. Nam.
The event team will handle it. [whoosh sound]
[somber music]
(Mina) I'm sorry.
[Sungwook sighs]
(Sungwook) How could he cancel on the day of the contract?
They even signed with the same workshop.
(Miyeong) It seems like they're trying to stop us from bidding on the project.
(Jinsang) This isn't the first time SE Trading has stabbed us in the back.
It's pretty clear that they have someone on the inside!
We have to find out who it is, sir!
(Sungwook) Are you saying there's a spy among us or what?
(Jinsang) How else would you explain this?
(Hagi) All right, everyone.
I also
Had the same thought once. [music stops]
But my conclusion
Was that I shouldn't be so quick to suspect APPELLO employees.
What's more important now is figuring out another way to win the project.
Start thinking of alternative items.
- (Miyeong) Yes, sir. - (Jinsang) Gosh.
There are only ten days left. How about my dalgona keychain?
Let's wrap up here.
(Jinsang) Mr. Kang, my keychain... [door opens]
- There isn't much time... - I'm sorry, everyone.
(Mina) I'm sorry.
[Mina inhales] [door opens]
[grunts]
[phone vibrates]
[Lee Chan grunts]
(Lee Chan December schedule) [message notification sound] [sighs]
[beep sound]
[sighs]
(Lee Chan) My "before" photo.
Still, I'll do my best today.
Is she busy?
(Dareum)
[soft music]
[laughs] [taps]
She really does smile a lot.
[deep sigh]
[insects chirping] [music fades]
(Sungwook) Mr. Kang, please just go home today.
You pulled an all-nighter yesterday too.
(Hagi) We need to find an alternative.
If SE Trading wins the K-Wave project just as they launch their platform,
We'll lose all our investors.
(Jinsang) Then Mr. Kang, why don't we use my idea...
(Sungwook) Come on. Can't you read the room?
You're such a nuisance.
(Miyeong) Mr. Park, what about the traditional container?
(Yeongwoo) They said they don't produce wooden containers since the lacquer
- doesn't dry well in winter. - (Dareum) Okay.
(Yeongwoo) And mother-of-pearl containers are too expensive.
(Miyeong) What about traditional hairpins?
They're already collaborating with a different company.
[Yeongwoo sighs]
- (Miyeong) What about traditional paper? - Well,
They refused the collaboration offer. [Miyeong sighs]
(Hyesu) So we can't work with any of these companies?
(Yeongwoo) What should we do? [Dareum sighs]
It's going to be difficult to meet the deadline.
[Miyeong sighs] Everyone,
We should still try whatever we can.
- (Yeongwoo) Yes, ma'am. - (Wontae) Okay. [door opens]
(Hagi) Ms. Nam.
Where did you get this?
(Dareum) What?
This keychain.
[intriguing music] [tapping keyboard]
[mouse clicking] (Dareum) My mom says
She knows this knot artisan's apprentice
And received it from them.
(Korean knot artisan) [mouse clicking]
(Miyeong) The colors and design are incredible.
[employees react]
(Hagi) How do we contact her?
(Dareum) Well... [sighs]
Apparently, she likes to keep to herself,
So there's no guarantee we'll be able to see her.
But my mom said she'd try talking to her apprentice.
(Miyeong) Oh, dear. [employees react]
[music fades]
[Hagi sighs]
[intriguing music]
[message notification sound] (Hagi) I'll pick you up tomorrow morning, so get ready for a business trip.
Keep this confidential and don't tell anyone where we're going.
[inhales] "Confidential"?
(Keep this confidential) [whoosh sound]
Then...
Am I going there alone with Mr. Kang?
[car approaching]
Ms. Nam, get in.
Okay.
[door closes]
[music stops]
[Dareum inhales]
But...
Why are we keeping this business trip a secret?
We can't guarantee that SE Trading
Won't stab us in the back twice.
(Hagi) I want to proceed with this quietly until the contract
Is finalized.
[Dareum reacts]
(Dareum) Right.
We don't even know where the artisan is,
So it'll be difficult for them to steal this item.
But is there a reason why you're taking me?
Well, you have the closest connection with the artisan.
(Dareum) Oh...
(Hagi) And more than anything,
You're the only one I can trust completely
At the moment.
[bright music]
[scoffs]
Did you forget how you used to think I was a spy?
[Dareum laughs]
Just leave this to me.
I, Nam Dareum, will show you around Jungsan.
[laughs]
[Dareum laughs]
(Miyeong) Okay. Please take care of that. [music stops]
All right. Thank you.
[Miyeong sighs]
I just contacted the supplier for natural silk thread.
We'll be able to get a sample by tomorrow,
So I want you to come up with ideas for what kind of products we can make.
- (Yeongwoo) Yes, ma'am! - (Wontae) Okay.
(Miyeong) Okay.
[clears throat]
But where did Ms. Nam
(Hyesu) go to speak with the knot artisan?
Did Mr. Kang go with her? [ominous music]
I'm not sure.
I don't know the exact details either. [laughs]
Okay.
[street sounds] [lively music]
[car beeps] [birds singing] (Dareum) Wow...
I can't believe we're passing by this place.
That's the neighborhood where I used to live.
And there's a market this way.
[Dareum inhales]
And there's even a lake park over there.
(Hagi) You really do know this place inside out.
Of course.
Everyone in this neighborhood knows me.
[music stops]
Is that "Nam Dareum"
This Nam Dareum right here?
[playful music]
(Kim Mija's daughter Nam Dareum accepted by SE Trading) [whoosh sound]
[gasps]
What is that?
I guess...
You really are a local celebrity. [Dareum sighs]
(Dareum) I can't believe this.
[taps]
[call connecting sound] [Dareum sighs]
Mom...
Mom.
What is this banner? Take that down.
Don't be silly.
I paid for that. Why would I take it down?
I'm hanging that there for at least six months. [Mija laughs]
[Dareum sighs] (Mija) I guess you're here, then.
Aren't you coming to see me?
I'm here for work, so I can't.
What about what I asked for? [music stops]
Well... Try going to your old high school.
(Mija) She'll only have a brief moment after lunchtime.
Okay.
Thank you so much, Mom. I'll call you again later.
(Dareum) Bye.
[call ending sound] [camera snaps]
[intriguing music]
Stop. Why are you taking photos of that?
You were the pride of the whole neighborhood.
(Hagi) "SE Trading,
Ms. Nam Dareum."
[groans]
[upbeat music]
(Hagi) The whole neighborhood must bring back memories for you.
(Dareum) Yes.
[Dareum laughs]
But it feels strange to be here with you, Mr. Kang.
[gasps]
(Dareum) My favorite snack bar!
[car engine revs]
I used to go there every day. [music stops]
[Dareum grunts]
Walk on the inside.
Okay.
[inhales] He does seem oddly sweet.
(guard) If you wait over there for a moment,
I'll call the cafeteria.
(Dareum) Okay. Thank you.
(Hagi) Thank you.
Over here.
(Hagi) Right.
[wistful music]
[students chatter]
(Dareum) Wow, it's been a long time.
- Why don't we sit down for a bit? - (Hagi) Sure.
[Dareum exclaims]
(Hagi) So this is your old school?
(Dareum) Yes.
[sighs]
[whoosh sound]
I used to sit here
And listen to music often. [music fades]
Everything's still the same.
- (student 1) Wow, he's so handsome. - (Dareum) What? [students squeal]
What?
[whoosh sound] [exciting music] (student 1) Hi. Are you a celebrity?
- (Hagi) No, I'm not. - (student 2) Are you an actor? A model?
(student 3) You're so handsome. Do you have social media?
(student 4) Can I take a selfie with you?
[Hagi grunts] (student 3) You're so handsome.
(Dareum) Oh, gosh... [camera snaps] [students chatter]
- (Dareum) You guys... - (Hagi) I'm not a celebrity.
(student 1) You're so handsome!
[students continue chattering]
[Dareum grunts]
[snatches] [Dareum grunts]
(student 2) What?
(students) Wait! [upbeat music]
[students chatter]
[music stops] (Byeola) What?
Isn't that Dareum?
(Insadong, my house) All right, everyone. [bright music]
(Today's Mission: Find a Hot-Selling Item) Today, I'll show you how I prepare for a buying trip.
All right. [sparkling sound]
(Aseul Aseul Enter website)
I don't have a car,
(Licensed for years, taking a cab again) so I usually take a cab to the market.
[sparkling sound]
This is where I bought the strawberry panties.
I'm with the owner here.
I'm going to try selling this sexy underwear.
I like to see and feel the products in person before I buy them.
(Mimi) You still have those sitting in inventory.
[falling sound]
[bright music plays]
[tapping keyboard] [music stops]
(Seula) I told you to be quiet while I recorded.
[Mimi sighs]
What are you doing instead of working these days?
This is work.
[scoffs]
(Seula) These days, you have to promote your products through videos.
Just wait and see. Orders are going to start pouring in soon.
(Mimi) Yeah, right.
Refund requests poured in after you sold those padded bras last time.
(Seula) Hey. [cat hissing sound]
I got scammed because I was new to the business. [intriguing music]
How was I supposed to know [whoosh sound]
That the pads would move to the side? [swishing sound]
That's what I mean.
(Mimi) You should stick to what you know.
Why sell sexy underwear that you've never even worn before? [cat meowing sound]
You idiot.
Jeez...
[phone vibrating]
[Seula exclaims]
I must've received an order.
[message notification sound] What?
Dareum must be visiting our hometown.
(Mimi) What?
- Without even telling us? - (Seula) Right?
[message notification sound] (Byeola) Seula, Dareum came to our school with this handsome guy!
[message notification sound] It must be her boyfriend!
[message notification sound]
(Seula) What? Boyfriend?
(Mimi) Wow...
Who was that guy again?
[music stops]
[Hagi sighs] [Dareum grunts]
[Hagi clears throat]
[Dareum laughs]
You're really popular with the high school girls.
You were popular back in school, weren't you?
(Hagi) Well...
A bit, I guess.
[laughs awkwardly]
Right.
You really...
Don't lie. [laughs awkwardly]
(Hagi) What about you?
What were you like in school?
[Dareum laughs]
(Dareum) What do you think?
Cheerful, like you are now.
[Dareum reacts]
Full of energy... [Dareum reacts]
(Hagi) And a social butterfly
Who knew everyone?
[Dareum reacts]
Wrong! [Dareum laughs]
To be honest,
I didn't have any friends for a while.
[lonely music]
Even during lunchtime,
I sat alone for most of the time.
So
Seeing kids like that
Bothers me a little.
It's a feeling only people who've been alone can understand.
(Hagi) Maybe that's why
You're always considerate of other people's
Feelings.
[laughs]
(Dareum) Still,
I have a lot more good memories here.
I found someone who gave me strength,
So I was able to fight through it.
Who's that?
[Dareum inhales]
(Dareum) Well...
My...
[laughs]
First love.
[Dareum laughs]
Seeing him work hard
Motivated me to work harder as well.
Anyway,
I'm very grateful for him.
I'm glad...
(Hagi) you had someone like that
Back then.
[laughs]
(Eunjeong) Excuse me...
[music fades]
Are you the people looking for my mentor?
(Dareum) Yes!
- Hello. - (Eunjeong) Hello.
(Eunjeong) Well...
I did come because Mija asked me to, but...
If you just tell us the location,
We'll try talking to her ourselves.
Please don't tell her you got the address from me.
(Dareum) Of course.
It won't be easy...
(Eunjeong) But do your best.
Good luck!
[ding sound] (Dareum) What?
[intriguing music]
[music stops]
[birds singing] [lively music]
(Dareum) Excuse me. Anyone here?
Hello.
(Hagi) Hello. [man 1 reacts]
Do you know where Ms. Im is?
(man 1) She's over there.
- (Hagi) Thank you. - (Dareum) Thank you.
[music fades]
(woman 1) Wow, look at the color. It looks delicious.
[woman 1 exclaims]
- Bring some more chives. - (woman 2) Okay.
- (woman 1) Good. - (Hagi) Hello.
(Dareum) Hello.
(woman 1) What?
Who are you?
(Hagi) We're from a company in Seoul called APPELLO.
This is Ms. Im Cheongrim's home, right?
(woman 1) What?
How did you know she was here?
[Hagi exhales]
Cheongrim!
Someone's here for you!
Come out here!
[door opens]
[dramatic traditional Korean music] [door closes]
[music stops] [birds singing]
[elegant traditional Korean music]
(Certificate of Merit for Craftsmanship Transmission)
[Dareum grunts]
[rustles]
Ma'am,
This is the proposal we've made in advance.
(Traditional Knotting Project)
(Hagi) APPELLO is a fashion platform that curates designer brands
From Korea and around the world.
And we're trying to bring traditional craftsmanship
And contemporary design together.
We believe we can introduce your work to the world...
What about production?
(Hagi) Don't worry, ma'am.
The factory has more than enough technical expertise
[thuds]
(Cheongrim) Factory?
Forget it.
(Hagi) If you're not happy with the factory we've chosen...
(Cheongrim) No.
I have no intention of working with profiteers.
[exhales]
Get out.
[birds singing] [faint dog barking]
[Dareum sighs]
What should we do?
[faint sigh]
(Hagi) You've already done more than enough here.
I'll give you a ride to the terminal, so head back to Seoul first.
What about you, Mr. Kang?
[uplifting music]
I'm going to convince Ms. Im.
(Hagi) Seeing her work in person
Made me certain of this.
[sighs]
Then...
I'll stay too.
I'll do whatever I can to help.
What are you going to do?
(Dareum) Well...
Whatever I can.
(Hagi) Ms. Nam.
[door creaks] [music stops]
[smacking sound]
[exhales]
[Dareum grunts] [lively music]
(Dareum) Gosh! [woman 1 grunts]
As a fellow Korean,
I can't just leave when you're making
A huge pile of kimchi?
I'll help you out a little.
Should I put the seasoning inside the cabbages?
[woman 1 laughs]
My goodness. You look so frail.
Have you even made kimchi before?
- (Dareum) What? - (woman 1) It's no easy task, you know.
(Dareum) What? [woman 1 laughs]
I've actually had some experience helping my mom.
[Dareum, woman 1 laugh]
Hurry up and help out here.
Oh, right.
(woman 1) Spread the seasoning inside.
- (Dareum) Like this? - (woman 1) Yes, that's it.
(Hagi) Hi,
There's an extra set of strong hands from Seoul here.
[women laugh]
[women chatter] That must be heavy. Let me help.
This must be pretty heavy.
[Hagi grunts] [comical sound]
[grunts]
That's a lot.
(woman 1) He's pretty frail too.
[woman 1 laughs] - (Dareum) I'm sure he'll be useful. - (Hagi) I'll put this here.
(woman 1) Both of you are so frail. [Hagi grunts]
He has no strength at all.
- I'm sure he'll be of some use. - (man 2) Help me out here.
(woman 1) He looks like he won't even be able to hold chopsticks.
[everyone laughs] [music fades]
(I only see you, Park Seojin) [birds singing]
(Mija) Hey!
[music: Park Seojin's "Push Push"] - Scrub, scrub - (Eunjeong) Mija!
(Mija) With love
(Eunjeong) Scrub the grime in your heart
[Mija cheers] [Eunjeong laughs]
[Eunjeong, Mija cheer]
Did you talk to Dareum?
Yes, of course.
(Eunjeong) She came with a colleague. [music stops]
She looked really busy.
- (Mija) Right? - (Eunjeong) Yeah.
She seems to be having a tough time after entering a big company
(Mija) in Seoul.
Well, it's only natural. It's SE Trading.
She must have loads of work.
SE Trading?
SE? That's strange.
It wasn't SE. [screeching sound]
What do you mean,
It wasn't SE?
- Pello. - (Mija) What?
(Eunjeong) It was something like...
Pello or something.
- (Mija) What? - (Eunjeong) Hang on. [rustles]
Right. APPELLO.
It was APPELLO.
(Mija) What?
(Nam Dareum)
What is this?
"APPELLO"?
[comical sound] [playful music]
[plops]
[woman 2 grunts]
- (Hagi) Ms. Nam. - (Dareum) Yes?
(Hagi) Be more thorough.
Don't just spread it. You have to coat the leaves.
Work it into the layers like this.
Let it seep in.
Like this.
(Dareum) Like this?
Like this?
Look, it's already gone completely limp.
Do it more gently, okay?
With sincerity.
[laughs awkwardly]
You seem very thorough...
With everything.
When I start something,
I have to see it through until the end.
[laughs awkwardly]
[music stops]
[Hagi sighs]
I'm wearing these gloves again.
(Dareum) What?
[sighs]
I thought I'd never wear them again after taking my cast off. [squishing]
(Dareum) Mr. Kang.
Did you actually wear...
Those rubber gloves?
[bubble popping sounds] [intriguing music]
[bubble popping sound]
[laughs]
(Dareum) Back then, you said,
[comical sound] "I have to watch my front and back when I'm with you"
[bubble popping sound] and snapped at me.
But I guess you wore them.
Fine, I did!
[Dareum laughs] (Hagi) Happy?
(Dareum) You said you wouldn't wear them.
Jeez...
(Dareum) They were nice, right?
[Dareum laughs]
(Hagi) Whatever.
Just do this properly.
(Dareum) I am.
(Hagi) They're all limp... [doors open] [music stops]
(Eunjeong) Mija!
Mom.
[Dareum grunts] [Mija sighs]
How did you...
[huffs]
[sighs]
[thuds]
(Mija) You! [Mija huffs]
Give me those gloves!
- (Dareum) What? - Just go
And help them move the containers.
Give me the gloves!
(Dareum) Okay...
[huffs]
[calm music]
(Mija) Move.
[squelches] [sniffles]
Mom...
Ms. Im.
[Mija reacts]
Can you please help my daughter out?
She never does anything halfheartedly.
If you help her, I'm sure she'll do an amazing job.
Right.
[Mija laughs awkwardly]
This looks amazing. [laughs]
You bought really good cabbages.
They look great.
You have to wrap them thoroughly like this.
And add lots of seasoning.
[Mija grunts]
[music stops]
[Minwoo sighs]
Look at you.
You're looking pretty good today.
Maybe I shouldn't have applied for a group lesson.
If everyone falls in love with me,
That would be troublesome.
[taps] [smacks lips]
(Mimi) Take a long step back,
And move down.
One. [intriguing music] [trembling sound]
Two.
[Minwoo exhales] One.
[Minwoo grunts]
Two. [Minwoo exhales]
One.
Minwoo, lower your arms. [music fades]
[Minwoo gasps] [swish sound] [playful music]
(Mimi) Tighten your core. [Minwoo gasps] [creaking sound]
Straighten your back and tighten your core. [whoosh sound]
[Minwoo grunts] Straighten your back. Tighten your core.
Minwoo, lower your arms. [Minwoo groans]
Tighten your core. [Minwoo gasps]
That's it. Hold on.
Two. [Minwoo exhales]
Again. One.
[grunts] Lengthen your spine as you inhale.
- Draw your ribs in. - (student 1) Gosh!
You should raise your arms. [comical sound] [Minwoo groans]
You have no strength at all. [smacks]
My goodness. [students scoff]
Two...
- (Mimi) Minwoo, please get up. - (Minwoo) Okay.
[Minwoo pants] (Mimi) Last one.
One. [Minwoo grunts]
[music stops] [faint dog barking]
[insects chirping]
[chattering]
[students laugh]
(student 1) Minwoo!
- Come on. - (Minwoo) What? [students laugh]
[intriguing music] - Let's go. - (Minwoo) Where?
(student 2) Why, of course,
We have to throw a welcome party for you.
[Minwoo laughs awkwardly] No, it's fine.
- (student 3) Let's go. - (Minwoo) Wait... [chattering]
- (student 1) What do you want to eat? - (Mimi) Bye.
- (student 3) Let's have meat. - (Minwoo) Aren't you joining us?
[fire crackling] [music stops]
[people chattering]
(Hagi) Ms. Nam, I'll take that.
(Dareum) Thank you.
(Eunjeong) Where did Mija go?
Tell everyone to come and eat.
(Dareum) Okay.
[insects chirping] [footsteps approaching]
Mom.
Thanks for helping.
[Mija sighs]
I worked so hard to raise you...
What on earth do you do at that company to work here like this?
To tell you the truth, Mom...
(Dareum) there's something I didn't tell you.
I...
[exhales]
I quit...
SE Trading.
I know.
You know?
I saw your business card that said APPELLO or something.
[sighs]
(Dareum) I'm sorry I lied to you.
You seemed so happy that I was working for SE,
And I didn't want to disappoint you.
I'm not sad that you quit a big company.
I'm sad that you didn't tell me
(Mija) what was going on.
[soft music]
Even when you were in school,
I wish you'd told me if you were having a hard time.
I know it was because you didn't want me to worry,
[inhales]
But sometimes I wonder if you can't trust me.
Whenever you hide things from me,
I feel so upset.
(Dareum) I'm sorry.
I won't do that anymore.
[Dareum sniffles]
But Mom.
Even if it's a small company,
My ideas can be reflected
And I can have my voice heard.
I...
[faint laugh]
Feel like I'm useful there.
That's why I like APPELLO,
And I'm happier here.
[sniffles]
(Mija) Then that's fine.
Wherever you work,
All I want...
Is for you to be happy.
[sniffles]
Thanks, Mom.
[sniffles] [pats]
[exhales]
[Dareum laughs] (Mija) Gosh.
[Dareum grunts] [Mija laughs]
[music stops]
[sniffles]
[boiling]
[people chattering]
- (Dareum) I should get more meat. - (Mija) Okay.
Ma'am, try some of this.
And this too.
Oh, sure...
[Hagi grunts]
(Mija) Please
Take good care of Dareum. [pouring]
She's new to the workplace,
So I'm sure she has a lot to learn. [thuds]
Well, not a lot.
Just...
A little bit.
[intriguing music]
But I'm sure she's very hardworking.
All our employees are hardworking.
(Mija) I see...
[laughs]
[inhales]
I guess there isn't much to compliment
About Dareum, then.
[sips] [music stops]
Ms. Nam
Is already a great employee.
[warm music]
She's always full of energy
And does her best,
(Hagi) so even if she's only recently joined us,
She's been a great help so far.
There's no need to worry, ma'am.
Is that so?
I did think Ms. Nam was very warmhearted.
(Hagi) I guess she takes after you.
(Mija) Oh, my! [laughs]
[Hagi laughs] My goodness.
How did you know?
To be honest,
Everyone who sees us says she takes after me.
[laughs] Really? [Mija laughs]
- (Mija) Let's clink glasses. - (Hagi) Sure.
[clinks] [Mija laughs]
(Mija) Wow... [Hagi exclaims]
You really know how to drink.
[Hagi reacts]
- Have another glass. - (Hagi) Sure.
[pouring] [Mija laughs]
[Mija exclaims] [Hagi grunts]
- Let me pour you some too. - (Mija) Okay.
[pouring] [Mija laughs]
[music fades]
By the way... [thuds]
Is Dareum...
Seeing anyone at work?
[ding sound] [intriguing music]
Or does she seem to like anyone?
[ding sound]
(Hagi) Excuse me? [comical sound]
Well, I'm not sure about that...
[sighs]
I'm worried
Since she doesn't seem interested in dating at all.
[Hagi exhales] [Mija grunts]
[Hagi clears throat]
But...
(Mija) you look so young.
[Hagi grunts] (Mija) By any chance,
Are you single?
Yes, I am.
(Mija) Oh!
Really?
[inhales] [swish sound]
Then...
What's your ideal type?
- (Hagi) Excuse me? - (Mija) I mean,
You said Dareum is warmhearted.
Do you not like women like her? [music fades]
It's not that... [footsteps approaching]
[thuds] (Dareum) Mom!
Jeez...
Don't say stuff like that.
Don't ask Mr. Kang such weird questions.
(Mija) I was just asking him his ideal type out of curiosity.
(Dareum) You're not supposed to ask questions like that at work.
- (Mija) Is that so? - And there's a reason why you shouldn't.
(Mija) Then will you get fired again when you just joined them?
[Dareum gasps] No way.
(Mija) What do I do? [sad music]
(Hagi) Ma'am...
The man your daughter likes...
Is actually me.
[street sounds] [music fades]
[elevator doors closing]
[button clicks]
(Miyeong) Director.
(employees) Hello.
Hello.
(Miyeong) What brings you here?
(Lee Chan) I'm just dropping by after my shoot.
Is the marketing team busy these days? [doors close]
[Miyeong sighs] We're working late every day
Because of the K-Wave project. [Miyeong laughs]
(Lee Chan) Hagi hasn't gone home yet, right?
(Miyeong) He's on a business trip.
With Ms. Nam.
- With Ms. Nam? - (Miyeong) Yes.
To bring in a knot artisan from Ms. Nam's hometown.
I don't think it's going well,
But they seem like they won't return until they succeed.
(Wontae) We're ready for the meeting.
- (Miyeong) Okay. - (Yeongwoo) Yes.
(Miyeong) Director, we have to start our meeting now.
What about you?
(Lee Chan) Well...
There's no one to see here, so I should get going.
(Miyeong) Get home safely, then.
(Lee Chan) Bye.
[footsteps fading]
(Nam Dareum)
(Event venue map Event introduction lines)
(K-Wave project APPELLO will win first place!)
[laughs]
[whoosh sound]
[ominous music]
(Lee Chan) My fan drew this character,
And it was so cute I memorized it.
[car beeps]
[whoosh sound]
It was Dareum.
[music stops]
(Dareum) Are you sure you're not coming with us? [insects chirping]
You're here for work.
(Mija) Do your best and convince Ms. Im,
- okay? - All right.
Get home safely, Mom.
(Mija) Okay.
(Hagi) Get back safely, ma'am.
Yes, Mr. Kang.
(Mija) Take good care of my daughter.
Gosh... [Hagi laughs]
(Mija) Bye, Eunjeong.
- (Eunjeong) Bye. - (Mija) Bye.
- (Dareum) Bye. - (Mija) Yeah.
- (Dareum) Get home safe. - (Mija) Yeah.
[insects chirping]
[clattering] [bright music]
(Eunjeong) It's nice to hear that you want to try learning this craft.
But it's difficult even for me when I've been learning for over ten years.
Ms. Im always says,
"Making knots is a form of spiritual practice."
She's been doing it her whole life, but she says it's still difficult.
Compared to her, I'm still taking baby steps.
[laughs]
I haven't even been born yet. [Eunjeong, Dareum laugh]
Anyway,
As you can see,
This cord made by braiding several strands of thread is called "ggeunmok."
And we're going to make decorative knots with this ggeunmok.
Then why don't you try it to get a feel for what it's like?
Let's sit over there.
I'll tell you the easiest one first.
This is one of the most basic knots,
Called the "dongsimgyeol knot."
- "Dongsimgyeol." - (Hagi) "Dongsimgyeol."
(Eunjeong) We're going to make a "ko."
The ko
- is this round hole here. - Right. The ko.
(Eunjeong) Take these two strands down here
And fold them through the second and third ko.
- Like this? - (Eunjeong) Wow! Great job.
- Good. - (Dareum) Okay. [music stops]
[Dareum mutters]
(Dareum) Fold this...
And put this up here...
Do I fold...
Do I fold this one? Or this one?
This...
- (Hagi) It's not that. - (Dareum) What?
Oh... [lively music]
- (Hagi) It's not this. - (Dareum) Okay.
- (Hagi) Put this under this one. - (Dareum) Oh, I see.
- This one first. - (Hagi) Yes, and then...
- (Dareum) Okay. - (Hagi) Place it through here.
- (Dareum) Oh, this one. - (Hagi) Right here...
- (Dareum) Here... - (Hagi) Yes.
- (Dareum) Here. Okay. - (Hagi) Yes.
(Dareum) Got it.
- (Hagi) That's right. - (Dareum) Like this?
[music stops] [insects chirping]
[faint laugh]
(Dareum) All done!
Making this in person
Makes it seem even prettier. I feel so proud.
(Hagi) You're right.
[Dareum smacks lips] [inhales]
I can understand how they say
It contains time.
(Hagi) I didn't know
Even such a small knot took so much work.
(Dareum) Right.
[crashing]
[clattering]
I was going to clean it myself.
- Thank you. - It's nothing.
(Hagi) It's fine.
Let us know if we can help with anything.
(Eunjeong) Gosh.
All my friends who used to learn here are gone now.
I'm the only official successor left.
[sighs] So if I don't do this,
This craft will be gone for good.
Please,
Convince Ms. Im.
(Eunjeong) At this rate, it's only a matter of time
Before Korean knot-making dies out.
The work is demanding,
And making a living with it is difficult.
Who would want to do this?
So whether they make it at a factory or anywhere else,
I just want to show the world that Korean knot-making exists.
[door opens]
(Cheongrim) Is this what you've been making knots for all this time?
Ms. Im...
If that's how you're going to do this, then leave.
(Cheongrim) Go and produce them at a factory and earn lots of money!
[lonely music] Earn money?
(Eunjeong) If that's really what I wanted, I would've quit already.
I'm doing this...
Because I want to protect it.
Someone has to keep holding onto it!
I should do what I can...
But why do you say...
That it's wrong,
Just because my way of protecting it is different?
[Eunjeong sniffles]
[door opens]
[Dareum sighs] [door opens]
[Dareum grunts] [music fades]
(Hagi) Ms. Nam.
Yes?
(Hagi) Will you... [insects chirping]
Come outside for a bit?
(Dareum) Oh...
Hang on.
[fire crackling] [night bird calling]
(Hagi) I put this here earlier,
But I felt bad about eating it alone.
(Dareum) Sweet potatoes...
[laughs] You know how to do stuff like this too?
[Dareum gasps]
(Hagi) Try it. [Dareum exclaims]
[gasps] [sniffs]
The smell is insane.
Be careful, it's hot.
[coughs] [bright music]
[Dareum exclaims] [Dareum pants]
(Hagi) Ms. Nam, are you okay?
[Dareum exclaims] [taps feet]
Just spit it out on my hand.
[gasps]
(Dareum) What? He's giving me his hand? [grunts]
No, it's fine.
[gulps]
[grunts] [laughs awkwardly]
Be careful not to burn yourself.
[laughs awkwardly] Thank you.
(Dareum) Why...
Is he being so nice to me?
[night bird calling] [fire crackling]
[music stops] [Dareum grunts]
(Dareum) This reminds me of my grandma.
She used to roast sweet potatoes for me when I was little.
You're lucky.
(Hagi) You have a loving grandmother...
[Dareum laughs]
And a mother.
[Dareum reacts]
Thanks to you,
I had a great time today.
[Dareum laughs]
(Dareum) What do you mean?
[inhales]
I got to have drinks with your mother.
[emotional music]
My mother passed away when I was in high school,
So I never got to drink with her.
[laughs]
Then I guess you crossed an item off your bucket list today.
I guess so.
[laughs]
(Hagi) What about you, Ms. Nam?
Do you have a bucket list?
(Dareum) Well... [laughs awkwardly]
[inhales] Watch a concert in the front row?
And raise a pet.
And...
Hear the words,
"I'm so glad I have you"
From someone.
Well... [laughs awkwardly]
I guess that's kind of cheesy.
(Hagi) Oh... [Hagi clears throat]
I guess I've been sitting too long in front of the fire. [Dareum laughs awkwardly]
It's hot.
- I'm going to walk for a bit. - (Dareum) Okay.
[music stops]
What about you?
Do you want...
To walk with me?
[wind blowing] [insects chirping]
(Hagi) I feel like...
I'll remember this day for a long time.
(Dareum) Me too.
I'm really glad
That I have you, Ms. Nam.
[lively music]
[laughs awkwardly]
My bucket list.
Ms. Nam.
(Hagi) You told me once
That you joined APPELLO
Because there was someone you wanted to meet.
[music stops]
[laughs awkwardly] Well, yeah.
(Dareum) I did.
(Dareum) What?
Why is he suddenly asking that? [intriguing music]
Be honest with me today.
(Hagi) That person you wanted to meet...
Was it me?
(Dareum) What?
Do you see me as a man?
Do you...
Think...
I'm...
Interested in you or something?
(Hagi) We're alone here right now,
- so you can be honest... - Wait!
(Dareum) Hang on.
Is that why
You were being cold to me and saying stuff about you being a CEO
And me being an employee?
That was the reason?
[Dareum exhales]
Well, yes. I know
Something like that can't happen between the two of us.
I clearly know who you like.
[music stops]
You know what?
[grunts]
Who's that?
[Dareum exclaims]
Well...
[sad music]
Who do I like?
[Dareum gasps]
[sighs]
You like Director Lee Chan!
- (Hagi) What? - (Dareum) You've liked him
For a long time!
[sighs]
(Hagi) What...
What did you say?
But don't worry.
I swear I'll keep it a secret,
And I don't have any prejudices at all.
[scoffs]
(Hagi) Hang on, Ms. Nam.
So you mean
You've been...
Thinking that I like guys?
But you do.
[scoffs]
[laughs]
[Hagi laughs] [music stops]
Ms. Nam.
I don't like men!
- (Dareum) What? - (Hagi) And...
I'm actually interested in a certain woman right now.
[music: "My Bias, My Boss" theme song]
(Dareum) What?
[whoosh sound]
[light clicks] [music stops]
[quiet music]
[door opens]
[dramatic music]
[whoosh sound]
[music stops] [writing sound]
(Epilogue)
[playful music]
[clears throat]
Should I pull it?
Oh, yes...
[Dareum grunts]
(Dareum) It's done.
[Dareum laughs awkwardly]
(Hagi) You get how to do it now, right? [music stops]
[Dareum reacts]
Try it again, then.
[rustles]
[faint sigh]
[Dareum laughs]
(Dareum) Wow...
This is the first knot I made with you. [rustles]
Did she say it was called a dongsimgyeol knot?
[music: "My Bias, My Boss" theme song]
[Hagi clears throat] [Dareum laughs]
Why were you startled?
I wasn't.
[inhales]
[whoosh sound]
(Dongsimgyeol knot "Forever bound together as one") [thud sound]
(Dareum) Who could he be interested in?
(Lee Chan) Let's take my car.
(Hagi) Take my car. [Dareum laughs]
[Seula, Mimi squeals] (Mimi) What's this turn of events?
(Minwoo) "That woman I'm interested in is you."
Why can't you say it? Why can't you?
(Lee Chan) Why don't we
Stay by each other's side from now on?
[knocks] [Dareum gasps]
[Lee Chan screams] [Dareum gasps]
(Hagi) Who is she meeting? [people squeal]
Don't date a guy like that.
(Dareum) Mr. Kang.
(Hagi) At least to me, you can say that you're not fine.